Mark Alaniz

 $markalaniz000@gmail.com \mid 361-455-8875 \mid Austin, Texas \\ \underline{https://github.com/Digald \mid https://www.linkedin.com/in/markalaniz/} \\ \underline{https://markalaniz.herokuapp.com}$

Computer hardware enthusiast and full-stack web developer specializing in the MERN stack. I enjoy seeing how my creative abilities and problem solving skills come together in order to build functional web applications that I can be proud of.

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Austin, TX UT Coding Bootcamp - Javascript Full Stack Web Development	2017-2018
Texas A&M University, Kingsville, TX B.S. Geology & Certificate in GIS • Summa Cum Laude	2014-2016
Texas A&M University, College Station, TX B.S. Geology	2010-2013

LANGUAGES & TECHNOLOGIES

Bootstrap, Express, CSS3, HTML5, Javascript, JSON, JQuery, Node.JS, RESTful API's, Sequelize, MySQL, React.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Git, Mocha, Chai, Firebase

SKILLS

agile, cross-browser compatibility, database schema design, layout and typography, GIT/GIT BASH, Heroku, interactive prototypes, mobile web design, object relational mapping, object oriented programming, quality assurance testing, responsive design, security and session storage, sessions, typography, user authentication, templating

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE	Тітеfrате
Hot Spotr	Apr. 2018

Full-Stack Development (Work in Progress)

- Hot Spotr is a web application that takes out the leg work of finding the best areas in Austin to target the appropriate demographics and competition for your business.
- React client side with Node, Express, and MySQL backend. Passport used for local authentication and Sequelize for our ORM.
- https://github.com/Digald/Hot-Spotr

• https://businessplanner.herokuapp.com/

JoJo's React Adventures

Front-End Development

- This project is a memory game built with React.js to show off the use of managing state. Try to click each image tile only once. The images shuffle on each click!
- https://github.com/Digald/JoJos-React-Adventures
- https://digald.github.io/JoJos-React-Adventures/

RuneScrape Mar. 2018

Full-Stack Development

- RuneScrape is a MongoDB web-scraper to bring you the latest Old School Runescape news all in one place.
- Mongoose is used to create models and perform CRUD functionality for the scrapped articles.
- https://github.com/Digald/RuneScrape
- http://runescrape.herokuapp.com/

RangeFront Feb. 2018

Full-Stack Development

- RangeFront is a full-stack ecommerce web page that manages a user's shopping experience from custom shopping cart to a stripe-powered checkout.
- Featured development tech includes MySQL with Sequelize, Passport.js, and Handlebars.js
- https://rangefront.herokuapp.com/
- https://github.com/Digald/RangeFront

BitBay Dec. 2017

Front-End Development

- BitBay tracks Bitcoin market data and allows users to search ebay for items priced in Bitcoin. Worked with a team of 3 others where I was in charge of learning Chart.js.
- All technology used for BitBay includes Chart.js, Bootstrap 4, jQuery, Moment.js, HTML5, CSS3.
- https://github.com/Digald/BitBay
- https://digald.github.io/BitBay/

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Texas Medicaid Contractor (Austin, Texas)
2016-2018

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant (Kingsville, Texas)

2015-2016

Mar. 2018